All right. So here we are, with a website or a front end
好了，我们这里有一个网站或者说前端
on top of some smart contracts that we've deployed,
它是建立在我们部署的智能合约之上的
doesn't really matter what it is right now.
它具体是什么现在不太重要
This is typically the interface that you'll see
这就是你通常能看到的界面
boiled down to a really, really minimalistic level.
一个真的非常非常简化的版本
Typically, you'll see something like connect function, right,
你通常会看到类似 "Connect" 这样的功能
and Metamask, or some other wallet connector thing will pop up,
紧接着 MetaMask 或是其它种类的钱包连接器就会弹出来
we'll hit Next we'll connect here
点击 "Next" 还有这里的 "Connect"
might even say something like connected.
可能还会显示一些 "Connected"(“连接成功”) 的字样
And we can also execute functions,
我们同样可以点击这个 "Execute"
we can interact with our smart contracts, we can confirm, etc.
这样就可以与我们的智能合约进行交互，并且确认操作，等等
Right? This is something you might see something like Avi right,
好，这可能和你在 "AAVE" 上看到的内容类似，对吧？
I'll hit Connect on the application,
我要在 "AAVE" 应用里点击 "Connect"
it'll say, hey, how would you like to connect?
它会说，“嘿，你打算选择那个进行连接”
I'll choose Metamask. I'm going to change my Metamask to main net, but you get the picture, right?
我会选择 MetaMask，并把它切换到主网络，你懂的，对吧？
This is a simple example of what that would look like.
这是一个简单的例子，展示了它可能是什么样子的
So what is actually going on in the browser when we connect
所以，当我们进行连接时，浏览器上究竟发生了些什么？
what is actually going on? And what do we actually need to do,
它发生了什么？我们有需要做什么？
we're going to right click, hit Inspect.
我们点击右键，选择 “检查”("Inspect")
And on the right side, we're gonna see our debugger here.
然后在右侧，就可以看到我们的调试器
Now if we go over to sources, on the top of our browser,
现在，如果我们前往“源代码”("Sources")，就在浏览器的顶部
you'll see a few things.
你就可以看到这么一些东西
If you look down over here, right, we'll see this URL, right, which right now is going to be my localhost.
如果你看这里，就能看到这个 URL，它就是我的本地主机
And we'll also see meta mask and Phantom and a whole bunch of other stuff.
我们还可以看到 MetaMask, "Phantom" 以及一大堆其它东西
These other things that we see here are going to be what's injected from our browser extensions.
这些我们看到的其它内容都是从我们的浏览器插件中注入的
The reason we see this meta mask thing here is because I've meta mask installed, right?
我们之所以能在这里看到这个 MetaMask 是因为我们安装了 MetaMask，对吧？
The reason I see Phantom here is because I have the Phantom app installed.
而我能看到 "Phantom" 的原因是因为我安装了 "Phantom" 应用
Meta masks, of course, being an EVM, wallet and Phantom being a Solana based wallet.
MetaMask 是一个 EVM 钱包，而 "Phantom" 则是一个基于 "Solana" 的钱包
Now what happens when we have these extensions installed
现在，当我们安装完这些扩展后，会发生些什么呢？
is they automatically get injected into a window object in JavaScript,
它们会自动注入到 JavaScript 中的“窗口”(window) 对象中
and in fact, we scroll down to here in the console,
其实，我们往下拉，拉到这，在“控制台”("Console")里
again, you can find console, you can click here and click anything up there.
再提醒一下，你可以点击这里找到“Console”，以及，这上面的东西你都是可以点击的
And we type in window.
然后我们输入 `window`
We'll see we have this big window object with all this stuff, right?
就可以看到这里有一个庞大的 "window" 对象，里面有一大堆东西
This window object represents this our window basically right?
这个 "window" 对象基本上就表示我们的窗口
Now if we scroll all the way to the bottom
现在，如果我们一直滑到底部
and we do window dot Aetherium. We also see an object here.
接着我们输入 `window.ethereum`，同样可以看到一个对象
Now this window dot Aetherium object only exists if you have a meta mask or meta mask like browser
这个 `window.ethereum` 对象只有在你拥有 MetaMask 或类似的浏览器插件时才会存在
or if you want to look at some other web three wallet
或者，如果你想看看其它的 Web3 钱包
you do window dot Solana. So Alana right
你可以输入 `window.solana`
and we see this window dot Solana.
接着我们就会看到这个 "window.solana"
Now let's look at a browser that doesn't have Metamask or phantom installed.
现在让我们来看一个没有安装 MetaMask 或 Phantom 的浏览器
What do you think is going to happen in the window now
现在你觉得 "window" 里会发生什么？
let's go ahead and right click hit Inspect. We'll go to the console.
我们来点击右键，"Inspect"，前往 "Console"
Now let's see what's going on in here.
现在让我们来看看这里发生了些什么
If we go to sources, we first off we don't see that Metamask or that Solana source here.
如果我们前往 "Sources"，首当其冲的是我们看不到 MetaMask 或 Solana 源了
And if we go to console, we still see window
如果我们前往 "Console"，仍然查看 `window`
if I let me zoom in a little bit. We still see window here.
让我来放大一点，我们再次查看 `window`
But if I do window dot Aetherium If we get nothing,
但如果我执行 `window.ethereum`，一无所获
or if I do window dot Solana, we also get nothing.
或者执行 `window.solana`，同样一无所获
So in order for our browsers to know that there's a Metamask, or that there's a phantom,
所以，为了让我们的浏览器知道 MetaMask 和 Phantom 的存在
those extensions automatically add these to our window objects,
我们需要这些扩展将它们自动添加到 "window" 对象中来
and that's something that we can check for in our JavaScript.
并且我们可以在 JavaScript 中进行检查
The reason these wallets are so important is built into them underneath the hood,
这些钱包之所以如此重要，是因为在内部构造中
they have a blockchain node connected to them.
它们与一个区块链节点相连接
And in order to interact with the blockchain, we always need a note.
为了与区块链进行交互，我们始终都需要节点
And you might have seen URLs from alchemy, or in FIRA
你可能是从 "alchemy" 或 "INFURA" 上获取的 URL
because you need them to interact with the blockchain,
这是因为你需要它们才能同区块链进行交互
Alchemy, and infura are examples of third party blockchains that
"alchemy" 和 "INFURA" 是第三方区块链中的例子
you can interact with and basically rent, right.
你可以与它们进行交互，基本上就是租用的形式
But you need them to create a provider, or a node to send your transactions to.
你需要它们创建一个 "provider" 或者说一个节点，才能发送你的交易
So you could do it in JavaScript, like something like this
所以你可以在 JavaScript 中进行这样的操作
is the alchemy documentation where you take that alchemy URL,
这是 "alchemy" 文档中的一个示例，你可以把 "alchemy" 的 URL 放到这里
you stick it into some object and use that to send your transaction.
将其放入某个对象中，然后用它来发送你的交易
This is a way that you could do it in the back end.
这就是你在后端上可以使用的一种实现方式
But on the front end, what you normally want to use is you just want to use the user's Metamask,
但在前端，你通常想用的是面向用户的 MetaMask
or their Solana or their wallet as the main wallet.
或是 Solana 或者其它主网络上的钱包
Now, there are a ton of other different types of wallets to connect,
目前，有很多不同类型的钱包可供连接
like ledger, mu, Coinbase, wallet, connect, etc.
比如 "Ledger", "MEW", "Coinbase", "Wallet Connect" 等等等等
And there are different ways to set those up.
并且它们也有不同的设置方式
But they all do the same thing where they expose some URL,
但它们做的事都是相同的，它们会在幕后提供一些 URL
they expose some node under the hood,
提供一些节点
they give us that URL. They give us that provider.
他们给了我们 URL，给了我们 "provider"
The way metamath Does it is with window dot Aetherium.
针对 MetaMask 的方式是 `window.ethereum`
Boom, this is now our URL. This is now our connection.
嘭，这就是我们的 URL，这就是我们的连接
In fact, if you go up to your Metamask, hit the little three dots, expand view. hit Add Network,
事实上，如果你打开你的 MetaMask，点击这里的三个小点，“展开视图”("Expand view")，点击“添加网络”("Add Network")
and then just hit the X so we can get to networks.
然后点这个 X，这样我们就到了“网络”("Networks")界面
You can see all of these blockchains that I have in here all have an RPC URL,
你可以看到，所有这里我拥有的区块链，都有一个 "RPC URL"
this the HTTP RPC URL connection of the blockchain No, that's running.
这些连接在区块链节点上的 "http RPC URL" 正在运行
I happen to have one running locally right now.
我现在恰好有一个本地节点正在运行
All of these also have a node RPC URL
它们全都有一个节点 "RPC URL"
and you can actually see them right in your meta mask right.
你可以在你的 MetaMask 上查看它们
This is connected to in Fira, these are all connected to in Fira.
这是连接在 "infura" 上的，这些都是连接在 "infura" 上的
It's all the exact same thing.
它们都是完全相同的东西
Meta mask just has a really nice way of taking that URL,
MetaMask 提供了一个非常好的获取 URL 的方式
sticking it in the browser for us in this window dot Aetherium or window dot Solana you know or whatever.
来到我们的浏览器，输入 `window.ethereum` 或者 `window.solana` ，诸如此类的东西
So this is the main thing that we need to know
这就是我们需要知道的主要内容
we need. We always need a connection with the blockchain.
我们总是需要与区块链之间有一个连接
And these browser wallets are an easy way to do that.
这些浏览器钱包就是一种简单的实现方式
Make sense? Great. Let's take this knowledge now. And let's apply it.
懂了吧？非常好，让我们运用这些知识，开始实践吧